Hopkins, Vivian C.; Papers ua902.003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- General Research, Writings, and Publication Materials, 1927-1979; 9.5 cubic ft.
  - Bacon Family Letters Photostats, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bacon Family Letters Typed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Bacon Fhorucher [Notes]", Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Bacon Notes", Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Bacon Quotations", 1953; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Bacon Speech", Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Bacon - Unsorted and Unnumbered", Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Baconian Theory", 1935; 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Ballou and Beecher", Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Barbara Rotundo, "Forms of Address: Reading Between the Lines" Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Beecher [Stowe] Letters Women's Archives", 1959; Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Beecher Stowe Letters [Written Copies]", Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Bennoch Letters - Pearson", 1957-1958; Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Bently on Baconian Theories", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Biblical Materials Concerning Satan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Bibliotheque Britannique, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Biechy [Article on Francis Bacon with Notes]", Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Biechy, Deleyre, and Patru [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "The Bitter and the Sweet: a Story Submitted to Story Contest [in] Good Housekeeping [Magazine] by Vivian C. Hopkins", 1947; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "A Brief History of Platoism" by Vivian C. Hopkins, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Blake - MacWhorter", 1954; Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Blake - MacWhorter" Oversized Material, 1954; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "Boas on Boyle and Bacon", Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "The Booker Washington Trilogy", Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Booksellers [Correspondence]", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Boys for Bacon", Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Brattleboro" (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - "The Broken Furrow" Short Story, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "Brooke Farm [Bibliography]", Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "Bundy on Bacon", Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Burns, Lamb, and the Devil of the English Romantics, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Butler and Hepsworth Dixon", 1958; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "By Nature: the Measure of a Work of Art Theory of Correspondence", Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Calvin", Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Canal Color Slides, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Canals", Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Carbon Carlyle Emerson Anderson", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Carbon Clinton and Canal", 1956; 1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Carbon Clinton Van der Kemp Am. Phil. Soc.", 1959-1961; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Carbon of Pierre", Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Carbon Whicher Review", Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Caroline Wells Healey Dall Article Review and Notes, 1954; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Catherine Beecher [Research and Notes]", 1954; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Cement [and DeWitt Clinton]", Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Chanson d'un Pilote", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Charles Adam [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Chesselden, 'Surprise Account'", Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Choate", Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "City Doctor" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story and Materials, 1977; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Civil War", Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "'Clinton to Clinton at Clinton' Edited by Harold W. Thompson, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Cochrone and Terry on Bacon", Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Collier Encyclopedia [Vivian C. Hopkins' Delia Bacon Article]", 1959-1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Columbia Library [DeWitt Clinton Correspondence]", 1959-1960; 1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Columbia U[niversity] Press [on DeWitt Clinton Publication]", 1961; 1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Condillac Destutt Tracy", Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "Copy of Speech Given at American Literature Group of the Modern Language Association, Chicago, Dec. 1953" (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "Correspondence about Delia [Bacon]", 1954-1956; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and Materials for Delia Bacon Book with Random House Publishing, 1954-1957; 1959-1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence and Notes for Delia Bacon Research with Libraries and Historical Societies, 1953-1955; 1957-1958; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Correspondence MSS", 1967-1969; 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Cotton Mather", Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "A Courtier of Elizabeth" and "One Loyal Subject" by Vivian C. Hopkins", Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Courtney Robert Hall Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "[Craig] Wylie's Revision Love Affair Chapter", 1957; Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "Craik and De Luc on Bacon", Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Creative Work, 'Second Avenue'", Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "Criticism of Clinton MS. Price and Burr", Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "D'Alembert [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Dante 'The Inferno'", Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Davis - F.W. Gilmer", Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "De Maistre [Article on Francis Bacon with Notes]", Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Delia Bacon and John Lord Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Delia Bacon and Myra Gaines, 1955; Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Delia [Bacon] Astronomy", 1955; Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Delia Bacon Bibliography, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "[Delia Bacon] Boston Materials", 1955; Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Delia Bacon Chronology Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Delia Bacon Complete Carbon, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Delia [Bacon] - Felger Letters", Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "[Delia Bacon Manuscript] Part Two Rough Draft", Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "[Delia Bacon Manuscript] Part Five Rought Draft", Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "[Delia Bacon Manuscript] Part Six Notes", Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "[Delia Bacon] N.Y. Lectures", Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "Delia [Bacon] Original Article and N.Y. Times Clips", 1961; Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "[Delia Bacon] Publishers - Requests of", 1954-1956; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Delia Bacon Theory Sent to Louis Marcer", 1961; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton and Astor", 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - DeWitt Clinton and Chancellor Livingston Dangerfield Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton Chronology", Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - DeWitt Clinton Diary Notes and Correspondence, 1957; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton and Education", Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "DeWitt Clinton and the Empire State" Manuscript Draft by Vivian C. Hopkins (1 of 2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "DeWitt Clinton and the Empire State" Manuscript Draft by Vivian C. Hopkins (2 of 2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton Early Copy", Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - DeWitt Clinton Erie Canal Research Notes and Drafts, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - DeWitt Clinton General Correspondence, 1957; 1959-1961; 1963; 1970-1972; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton and Iroquois", Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - DeWitt Clinton Letters, 1957-1958; 1961; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "[DeWitt Clinton Manuscript] Chapter Seven Carbon", Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton - Original Carbon Variations of Some Pages (Incomplete)", 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton Portraits", 1958; 1967; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton Renaissance Man Edition I", Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - DeWitt Clinton and Science Correspondence, Drafts, and Notes, 1971-1975; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - DeWitt Clinton Serial Publications by Vivian C. Hopkins (1 of 2), 1960-1962; 1964; 1967; 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - DeWitt Clinton Serial Publications by Vivian C. Hopkins (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "[DeWitt] Clinton Speeches", Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - DeWitt Clinton Untitled Manuscript Drafts, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - DeWitt Clinton and Van Der Kemp Notes and Correspondence, 1959-1960; 1962-1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Devil-Theory", Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Dial Notes [on Francis Bacon]" (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Diary, Iowa Farm Girl", 1972-1973; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "Diary of an Iowa Farm Girl," Serial Publication by Vivian C. Hopkins, Annals of Iowa, Volume 42, Number 2, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Dickens and Grant White on [Francis] Bacon" (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Donatello" by Hope Kia Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Dostoyevsky, 'The Brothers Karamazov", Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "E. Ms. Lectures Houghton List", Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Early Notes - Bacon", Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Early Stories, Vivian C. Hopkins", Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Edmonds Notes", Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Education Speech, April", 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Ellsworths [Notes]", 1861-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Emerson Bacon Carbon", 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Emerson Bacon Notes", Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Emerson Bibliography", Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Emerson Book Review in the New York Times, 1949 (Oversize 2)
  - "Emerson Editions", 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Emerson and Lucretius", 1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Emerson Notes for Lecture", 1953; Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Emerson Oakland Calif. Speech", 1961; Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Emerson and Politics", 1968; Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Emerson Research Notes, 1943; Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Emerson Serial Publications by Vivian C. Hopkins, 1948; 1951; 1958; 1960 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Emerson and the West", Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "Emerson and the World of Dream", 1969; Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Emerson and "The Young Americans" Dials III and IV with Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Emery [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Emily Dickinson Research Materials and Notes, 1950; 1955; 1959; 1968; Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Emily Dickinson Research Materials and Notes Oversized Materials, 1950; 1955; 1959; 1968; Undated (Oversize 4)
  - "Enq. Stratford and F.B. Society", 1955 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "ESQ [Emerson Society Quarterly], Darrel Abel", 1967 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Essex Institute Historical Collections Serial Publications, 1974; 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Eugene O'Neill Research Materials and Notes, 1957; 1960-1962; Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Eugene O'Neill Research Materials and Notes Oversized Material, 1957; 1960-1962; Undated (Oversize 4)
  - "Exercises for the 'American Scene'", Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - "Extracts from Thesis 'The Aesthetic Theory of Ralph Waldo Emerson' by Vivian C. Hopkins", Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - "Fable for Critics", Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Faculty Fellowship Proposal: "An Illustrated Monograph on Arthurian Localities", Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - "Fairchild V.D. Kemp", Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Family and Other Themes", 1927; Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - "The Faust Motif", Undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - "Faust Theory", Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "February Thaw" and Screen Prints (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "Fellheimer [Research Correspondence]", 1954-1955; Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - "Fifth Son in Exile" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - "Fitch Family Papers Yale [Notes]", Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - "Fireside Poetry", Undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - "Fireside Poetry" Oversized Material, Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "'Florence' [Short Story]", Undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - "Flowers and Delia Record to Francis", 1955; Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - "Folklore - Devil", Undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - "Fonsegrive [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - "For the Hopwood Major Awards, 'Pieces of Gold,' A Novel, Undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - "The Fortunes of Satan" Manuscript Draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Fourth Annual Faculty Lecture, DeWitt Clinton and New York State by Vivian C. Hopkins, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Fragments from American Georgics, Iow Number, February 1928" (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - "Francis Bacon in America 1800-1865" by Vivian C. Hopkins Manuscript Draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "'Francis Bacon in America 1800-1865' by Vivian C. Hopkins Typescript", Undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - "[Francis] Bacon Biography", 1957; Undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - The Francis Bacon Foundation Correspondence with Vivian C. Hopkins, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Francis Bacon Law Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Francis Bacon Manuscript Correspondence, 1956-1957; 1964; 1967-1968; 1972; Undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Francis Bacon Manuscript Drafts with Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Francis Bacon Notes" (1 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Francis Bacon Notes" (2 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "[Francis] Bacon Orig. Proposal", Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Francis Bacon Paper", 1951; 1959; 1961; Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Francis Bacon Paper" Oversized Material, 1951; 1959; 1961; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "Francis Bacon Rough Draft", Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Francis Bacon's Trial Articles and Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "French Criticism Bacon", Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - French Criticism of Bacon Research Proposal for the Research Foundation of State University of New York, 1961; Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Genesis", Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "George Keith in Jones' 'The Quakers'", 1957; Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Gibson - Addenda [to Bacon Bibliography]", Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Goethe Emerson First Draft", 1948; Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Goethe Faust [Notes]", Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Greenough Emerson", 1954-1955; Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Guggenheim", 1955; 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "The Harrowing of Hell" Materials, Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - "Harvard Presidents", Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Harvard University Press Advertisements of "Prodigal Puritan: A Life of Delia Bacon" by Vivian C. Hopkins, ca. 1958 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Harvard University Press [Correspondence and Materials]", 1958-1963; 1967; Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Hawthorne Bibliography", Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Hawthorne Lectures (Pearson)", Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Hawthorne Research Materials and Notes, 1950-1970; Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Hawthorne Research Materials and Notes Oversized Material, 1950-1970; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - Herman Melville Manuscript Proposal, 1972; Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Herman Melville Research Materials and Notes, 1951-1953; 1955; 1964; 1968-1970; Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Herman Melville Research Materials and Notes Oversized Materials, 1951-1953; 1955; 1964; 1968-1970; Undated (Oversize 4)
  - "Hiawatha Parody", Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Hibernicus Letters", 1959; Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - "History U[nited] Methodist Church [by Vivian C. Hopkins]", Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "Holmes [Notes on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "A Home of Her Own" Short Story, Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "The Houses of Robert Frost" by Vivian C. Hopkins, 1973-1975; Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "The Iceman Seen Through the Lower Depths" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "Illustrations for 'Sp[ires] of Form' Not Used", 1952; Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Incomplete Manuscript on DeWitt Clinton by Vivian C. Hopkins (1 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Incomplete Manuscript on DeWitt Clinton by Vivian C. Hopkins (2 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - "Indian Notes", 1958; 1960-1961; Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - "Indians - Bibliography", 1960-1961; 1970; Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - "'The Influence of Goethe on Emerson's Aesthetic Theory' by Vivian C. Hopkins", 1947; Undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - "Influence [of] Palissy on Bacon", Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "Int. Discourse [DeWitt Clinton]", Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "Introduction to Emerson's Theory of Art", Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Introductions and Texts to Whittier and Benet", Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Iowa - As I Grew to It" by Vivian C. Hopkins, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Irving 'The Devil and Tom Walker'", Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - James Fenimore Cooper Research Materials and Notes, 1948-1967; Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - James Fenimore Cooper Research Materials and Notes Oversized Material, 1948-1967; Undated (Oversize 4)
  - "James G. Percival [Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "James Russell Lowell to Charles Eliot Norton Paris, December 4, 1872", Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Jefferson [Notes]", 1956-1957; Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Jin OK on Witman", Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Job", Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Joel Henry Address and Funeral Mrs. Williams", Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "John A. King [Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "John Jacob Astor and DeWitt Clinton" by Vivian C. Hopkins, ca. 1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Joseph Henry", Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Kitchen Things' [Short Story]", ca. 1926; Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Kocher Prior McRae on Bacon and Leibritz", Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Kynaston-Snell [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "Lalande", Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Lambrechtsen Hist[ory] New Netherlands", Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Lauter on Emerson", Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "Leady Nations and Athenaeum Reviews and Review of the Bride", 1955; Undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "Learned Societies", Undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Leeds Almanack [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - "Leeds [Research Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Leon Howard on Bacon", 1953 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - "Leonard Bacon to Dr. Fayrer", Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - "Let the Five Burn!" Short Story, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - "Letters about Delia [Bacon]", 1959-1961; 1965; Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "The Letters of Thomas Wolfe", Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "Letters re. R.W. Emerson", Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "Lewis, 'The Strewtape Letters'", Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Life Magazine, "Satan's View of Man" by Mark Twain, 1962 (Oversize 2)
  - "Life of Adam and Eve", Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "The Life of Rev. Joel Hawes" Correspondence, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Life of Thurlow Weed Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - "Linnaeus", Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - "Love-in-a-Mist" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story, Undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Love is Enough" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story, Undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - "Lowell, Anna Cabot Jackson [Notes]", 1955; Undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - "MacWhorter Mathematics", Undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - "Maine de Biran", Undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - "March 6 '79 Speech [on DeWitt Clinton with Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - "M[argaret] Fuller Carbon", 1967-1968; Undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - "Margaret Fuller [Research Notes]", 1968; Undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - "Maria Mitchell [Research Materials]", 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Mark Twain Papers Correspondence to Vivian C. Hopkins, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Mark Twain Research Notes and Newspaper Clippings, 1968; Undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - "Mark Twain's Joan of Arc" by Mentor L. Williams with Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - "Marlowe Theory", 1956 (Oversize 4)
  - "Mary Moody Emerson", 1945; 1951-1952; Undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - "Maugers - Le Progrez et Avancement", Undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - "McCake Kocher Shachford", Undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - "McNamee on Bacon", Undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - "Melville Bibliography", Undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Melville, Hawthorne, and the Devil, Undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Melville and Shakespeare Article, Undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - "Melville Voyages", Undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - "Meredith, 'Lucier in Starlight'", Undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - "Miller ['The Crucible'] Article", Undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - "Milton, 'Paradise Lost' [Article]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - "Minor Transcendentalists - Selective Bibliography", Undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - "Mitchill 'Am. Botany'", Undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - "Morse Palfrey Henshaw", 1953; Undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - "Morse Palfrey Henshaw" Oversized Material, 1953 (Oversize 2)
  - "Ms. Emerson and Bacon Newsletter Article", Undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Nathaniel Hawthorne Letters Typed Copies, Undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - "Neal, John [Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - "New Haven West Association", 1954-1956; Undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - "New Letters from the Grimm-Emerson Correspondence", 1977 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - "New York City Background", Undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - New York Geology Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - "New York [Historical Society] Day Book", Undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings on Perry Miller, 1949; 1953; 1969; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - The New York Times Book Review "Bewitched, Bewildered - and Analyzed", 1959 (Oversize 2)
  - "Norman H. Pearson", 1954-1955; Undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - "Notable American Women [on Delia Bacon]", 1959-1960; Undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - "Notes on Restoration and Eighteenth Century Drama Mueschke by Graham Belcher", Undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Notes on Samuel Tyler, Undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - "O'Connor, William [Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - "Oeuvres - Bouillet [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - "An Offprint from Studies in English Literature 1500-1900, the English Renaissance Volumes, Number 1", 1965 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - "Ohio Canal, Steamboat, Railroad, N.Y. Harbour [DeWitt Clinton Notes]", Undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - "Oration on Benevolence", Undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - "Original Bacon Paper", ca. 1954; Undated (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - "Paine Letters", Undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - "Parable of the Plow" by Vivian C. Hopkins, Undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - "Peace" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story and Materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - "Periodical Criticism [Francis] Bacon", Undated (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - "Personal History of Lord Bacon" Photostats, Undated (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Photostat of Arkins and Chesselden's "Surprising Account of the Devil", Undated (Oversize 2)
  - Photostat of Correspondence from Van der Kempt to John Linklaen April 27, 1818 from the New York Historical Society, Undated (Oversize 2)
  - Photostats of Delia Bacon Correspondence and "His Author's Apology and Claims", Undated (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Photostats of Delia Bacon Correspondence and "His Author's Apology and Claims" Oversized Material, Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "Pierre Amboise 'Vie de Bacon'", Undated (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - "The Pilgrim Trust" Newspaper Clippings, Undated (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - "Pindar Puff", Undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - "Poe - Hundley, Eveleth Spiritualism", Undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Poe Research Materials and Notes, 1964; 1968; Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Politics [DeWitt Clinton Notes]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Possible Additional Material [on Satan]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Potter Alonzo ed. Bacon Essays", Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Preface and Criticisms [of DeWitt Clinton]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Prodigal Puritan: A Life of Delia Bacon" by Vivian C. Hopkins Reviews, 1959-1961; Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Prodigal Puritan: A Life of Delia Bacon" by Vivian C. Hopkins Reviews Oversized Material, 1959-1961; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "Prodigal Puritan" by Vivian C. Hopkins Typescript (1 of 2), Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Prodigal Puritan" by Vivian C. Hopkins Typescript (2 of 2), Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Professor B. Silliman Notes, 1957; Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)